ORIGINAL STORY SWEET HOME
BY CARNBY KIM AND YOUNGCHAN HWANG
CHA HYUN-SU, 19-YEAR OLD HIGH SCHOOLER
CURRENTLY REFUSING TO ATTEND SCHOOL
HIKIKOMORI WITH HISTORY OF
HABITUAL SELF-HARM
MOM
HYUN-SU, ARE YOU SURE YOU AREN'T COMING?
It'll be a good change of scenery.
You haven't been out of your room
in so long.
MOM
WE'RE LEAVING
RICE IS IN THE FREEZER.
MAKE SURE YOU EAT, OKAY?
Load ammunition.
How long is Hyun-su
going to behave like that?
Why didn't you do anything
to make sure he never got this way?
Dad.
It's not Mom's fault.
Why are you yelling at her?
Don't give me attitude.
This family's falling apart.
You're ridiculous. Since when do you care?
I don't know why I had any children.
They're never grateful for anything.
Stop. Both of you.
This is a family trip.
Don't be like that.
Sure.
It's all my fault.
Dad.
Dad!
Is that Hyun-su?
Where the hell have you been?
Don't be like that.
The poor boy must be devastated.
He looks like a mess.
Hyun-su.
I really didn't want to come outside.
But I couldn't believe it.
Only 30 million won.
You're basically telling me to die.
How am I supposed to get by with this?
How can I live on this
for the rest of my life?
What do you want me to do?
-Drag him out.
-Take him.
How can I live?
-What do you want me to do?
-Take him out.
Hurry.
How could he just leave him here
like this?
Why is he so cold?
TRENDING
MONSTER, STATE OF ALERT, NOSEBLEED
AUDITORY HALLUCINATION,
PANIC BUYING, SHELTER, CHAOS
TRENDING
MONSTER, STATE OF ALERT, NOSEBLEED
Hey, I'm on my way.
The elevator isn't working,
so I'll be late.
No, the elevator is out of order.
I'm not lying.
I can't hear anything.
Hello?
Oh, no!
Just go.
I'm resting.
I'm hungry…
It's you.
Thanks for your help.
LEE SU-UNG
Su-ung.
Someone had to do it.
AUGUST 15TH SATURDAY
There's no service, is there?
I'm checking his family's phone number.
I should let his family know.
SATURDAY, AUGUST 15
What are you doing?
They can't see him in person.
This is the least we can do.
It'd be better if his family
didn't see him like this.
No.
It wouldn't be.
Damn it, the motion sensor
isn't working either.
Why is it my fault?
It's not even my problem…
The world's just so fucked…
Excuse me.
That's how the world is.
What hell do I know?
-Excuse me.
-Why is it my fault…
It's not my fault, and now
they want to get rid of me?
I want to kill them all.
Manager Han.
Manager Han, that son of a bitch.
Manager Han!
Excuse me.
Ji-su.
Don't go near him.
He might kill you.
Watch out!
My daughter isn't back yet.
You can't block this.
If anything happens to Min-ju,
it's all your fault!
-Please calm down.
-Block it.
Please wait.
I said, wait.
She's here.
I'll go get her quickly.
Open it. Please?
No.
Who are you to say no?
Do you know who I am?
I can't let this place fall into danger.
Stop, please.
Please open it.
It's working.
What's going on?
EMERGENCY ALERT
Is it an epidemic?
That man said he was going to the hospital
this morning.
Did the hospital do a test?
It must be the radiation.
SUPERMARKET
THOSE WITH THE FOLLOWING SYMPTOMS
MUST BE QUARANTINED IMMEDIATELY
NOSEBLEEDS, BLACKOUTS,
OR SUDDEN AGGRESSIVE BEHAVIOR
7,800 WON
NEW MESSAGE
How come you're so calm?
I am extremely shocked
and nervous right now.
That man…
No, that thing…
Do you think it's dead?
Probably.
Let's all go home.
What are we doing sitting here?
Won't the rescue squad come?
Do you not see this?
We're all screwed.
Our country won't go down like this.
Right, Military Man?
Yes. You're right.
If you stay calm and wait--
I can wait at home!
There must be an emergency shelter nearby.
Where exactly?
If we drive--
The underground parking lot
is blocked, too.
We have to go up!
Does anyone live on the seventh floor?
Me.
Hey, we can go up together.
Wait a minute.
If you're going up, we should all go up.
Don't you agree?
Let us all go.
-All right.
-No.
Wait. We need to block the entrance first.
Let's wait and see--
You can block, or wait.
Do whatever you want.
I'm going up.
-Wait.
-You can't.
You punks!
Where do you think you're running away to?
You selfish cowards trying
to save yourselves.
You're just worried about your shop.
I can't believe you just said that.
Byeong-il. Come here.
Do you all want to get killed?
Come here. Now!
He's right.
If we open the entrance,
we'll all be dead.
Move aside. Now.
You don't know what's out there.
I won't move aside!
-Come on.
-Why are you doing this?
-Stop.
-Don't do this.
-Come on.
-Stop.
What's that?
-What's that noise?
-What's that?
-What is that?
-Move back.
Jeez.
What are you looking at?
Is that a bite mark?
Stop right there!
Byeong-il.
Check him. Go and check him.
It's a bite. He's been bit!
Oh, goodness.
I got him!
You saw me, right?
Look at the bite mark on his shoulder.
I got him.
Bastard.
Zombie bastard.
It's all okay. It's fine.
8 HOURS LATER
It's not a disease.
It's a curse.
CRUCRU
IT'S NOT A DISEASE. IT'S A CURSE.
They complained of frequent nosebleeds…
…and auditory hallucinations.
The cause could not be determined.
They weren't from here originally.
They came here
because they showed symptoms.
They turned into miserable,
desperate beings.
Every prediction was wrong.
It suddenly begins one day
and it never stops.
I was consumed by it, too.
Humans will not be able to overcome this.
If you have symptoms,
kill yourself before it's too late
because being alive will harm others.
But if you decide to live to the end,
there's something you must know.
-That is…
THERE IS NO INTERNET CONNECTION
REFRESH
Nothing's working.
Will it still be there?
RAMYEON
There's probably no one out there, right?
I can't see.
I heard you.
I…
can't see.
I can't see.
I can't…
We have to kill him.
Kill him?
Yes, of course.
Can you do it?
Me?
You're the leader.
-I am.
-Yes.
He's still human, though.
Come on.
Seung-wan, have you ever seen a movie?
If you let the one who got bit live,
then everyone dies.
It's okay because it's self-defense.
Right, Seok-hyeon?
Won't he die of starvation
if we just leave him?
What if he gets hungry and eats everyone?
-We should do something.
-"We should do something."
Knock it off.
Seok-hyeon, you go in.
What?
Yes.
-Jae-heon, someone is in there.
-Three…
two, one…
Two…
-Do you think it's a person?
-One…
It's a person.
They're telling us the pass code.
Two, one, three, two…
Thank you.
I thought I was going to die.
-What happened--
-A burglar
came in.
How long have you been like this?
It's been a few days.
Did something happen outside?
I heard strange noises.
You should see for yourself.
Okay.
Wait.
I thought I better carry something, too.
Let's live together in one place
until the rescue squad comes.
It's safe to be together.
Where will all of us go?
The daycare center.
It's relatively safe
because it's far from the entrance.
It will also be better
to sleep there than here.
I won't allow it.
-No.
-Who are you to say no?
She's director of the daycare.
Scumbags.
Pieces of shit!
You ignored me when I begged.
You're shameless!
Your daughter probably
needs someone's help, too.
That's why I'm saying I'll go. Let me go.
You can do whatever you want
after I leave.
What about you?
Are you okay with dying?
Do you have a plan?
There's no internet or phone service.
How can you be sure where she is?
-Still--
-First, you have to live.
Otherwise you won't be able to find
or see your daughter.
Please calm down
and help us.
I'll be sure to help you later.
Do whatever you want.
This door is open.
I don't think you should see this.
NOW IT'S YOURS
Did he kill himself
because the world is doomed?
No, he's been dead for over a week.
How do you know?
It just seems like that, no?
AUGUST 25, TUESDAY
SUICIDE
Should I just kill myself now?
At least then
I'd die a human.
Dad, don't go. It's too dangerous.
Don't cry, Su-yeong.
Take good care of Yeong-su while I'm away.
All right?
-Dad.
-Don't cry, Su-yeong.
Monsters might come if they hear us.
You know
I was in the special forces, right?
I'll come back with food.
Yeong-su, listen to your sister, okay?
Get out of there.
Get out of there!
-Dad!
Dad!
Go away!
Go away, monster!
Help us!
Please help us!
I…
THEY MIGHT COME IF THEY HEAR ANYTHING
THOSE THINGS DON'T DIE
Dad!
-Dad!
DO YOU WANT TO SAVE THE KIDS?
IF YOU MAKE A CALL AND LEAVE THE PHONE ON
IT'LL MAKE A NOISE
WHEN A MONSTER IS NEAR YOU
EMERGENCY
COME WHEN YOUR MIND IS MADE UP
I think
I better stay home.
I think you should come with us.
No.
I don't want to burden you anymore.
I'll find my own way to survive.
-Still…
-Okay.
Take care of yourself.
Everyone has their own way of living.
I'll be fine.
Of course, I'll be fine.
What's wrong with him?
Salute!
We met in the elevator last time.
Right. I'm Lee Su-ung.
You live in Room 1305.
And you're in Room 308.
I live in Room 1009. I'm Son Hye-in.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Ryu Jae-hwan.
Does anyone have sunscreen?
What?
-I'll look for it.
-Okay.
You don't have to look for it.
Anyway, I'm No Byeong-il.
We're neighbors, but we've never…
Wait a minute.
You're not a familiar face.
Right.
She doesn't really talk.
Oh, I see.
You seem to know everything, ma'am.
Don't call me, "ma'am."
I'm sure I'm much younger than you.
Pardon? What makes you so sure?
Where is he?
-Oh my God.
-Where is he?
-Who?
-Seok-hyeon, who are you looking for?
-That thug!
That thug did this to me!
Son of a bitch.
You go your way.
I'll go mine.
How do you feel?
Do you feel like biting into people
and tearing them apart?
Which floor are you going to?
It's okay between us. We killed together.
Shut the hell up or go downstairs.
I don't want to.
It'd be freaking embarrassing
if I changed into something like that.
I'll kill you if you change.
Likewise.
I think this works for you.
Walk carefully.
I'm Han Du-sik.
And you are?
I'm Cha Hyun-su.
A slow speaker.
How
can I save the kids?
What do you mean by how?
You'll have to go.
Should I go?
I used to be a legend in Cheonggyecheon.
You know how you can get a tank made there
if you have a blueprint?
That means I can transform your stick
into something more useful.
-Give me that.
-Pardon?
Give me that stick.
Oh, the weapon.
Honey.
You didn't even notice I was gone.
Bring the eggs. Now!
Stupid bitch.
Jeez.
SUPERMARKET
Bite him.
Bite him hard.
It's done.
Hey.
CERTIFICATE OF MERIT
FIRST LIEUTENANT HAN DU-SIK
They still move around
with their heads chopped off.
A kitchen knife won't work.
But this will do.
Can I kill them with that?
No, you can't.
How do you know?
I just do. Avoid them at all costs.
If you come across them,
run for your life.
No.
Don't get caught in the first place.
Then please lend me that canon.
No.
It isn't stable,
so it can fire only a few shots.
I fired earlier.
I'll fire again if it breaks in.
The last shot is for me.
So I can go easy.
I can't see.
I found you.
Don't run…
Where are you?
Man, everything's melting already.
They'll all go to waste.
Hey, can't you see they're all going bad?
The power went out.
What do you want me to do?
How dare you talk back to me?
Well…
Can you be in the management office?
I need to check the electrical room.
I saw some places with lights on outside.
A blackout would affect
the whole district.
Only this building is experiencing issues.
I'll find out when
I go to the electrical room.
That's all the food we have,
so we have to hurry.
What? Hey, do you think this is all yours?
Don't be ridiculous.
We'll have nothing
if everything melts, anyway.
-Why don't we hand out--
-Be quiet!
I'll go.
Hey!
What are you doing?
You're stealing!
It's an emergency.
Hey!
Hey! Why you…
I can't believe the way these
punks are treating me, goddamn it.
Damn it.
This is all because you look down on me,
you bitch.
It was charging.
I don't know how long it'll last.
One more thing.
Be careful.
What do you do in this situation?
Isn't there a firefighters' manual?
We have to calm people down
and make them act collectively.
Food and drinking water must be secured.
And an escape route, as well.
Most importantly,
we need to understand the situation.
What about the cameras?
They can only help so much,
since there's only a few of them.
-There must be recordings.
-We need a password.
The security guard must know it.
The building was blockaded…
Not to lock us in,
but to protect us?
Hey.
You shouldn't go there.
Why not?
My dog's been barking like this.
I'll be careful.
What?
What's wrong? Are you scared?
Is something there?
Okay.
Su-yeong.
I'm scared.
It's too dark in here.
It's okay.
We'll be fine.
Dad.
He'll be back soon.
Kids. I'm here to help you.
Sir.
Please save our dad.
What?
Dad
fell down.
I know.
Maybe he's still--
Nobody can survive a fall
from the 12th floor.
There's a man on the 14th floor
with a lot of food.
You're hungry, aren't you?
You won't stay here by yourselves,
will you?
We need to go into the hall
where monsters are running wild.
Are you ready?
How old are you guys?
I'm nine years old and my brother is six.
Those are perfect ages to fight monsters.
Don't worry.
I'll protect you.
FIRE HYDRANT
Protect them?
Is that what you want?
Are you okay?
Get away from me.
Go!
Yes, you always liked to act cool
in front of the weak.
And then what happened?
It was my fault.
CHA HYUN-SU
Come out!
-It was my fault.
-It wasn't your fault.
Bastard!
It was your fault!
You're a sad case.
It was unfair.
Die.
Yes.
It was unfair.
BASED ON SWEET HOME
BY CARNBY KIM AND YOUNGCHAN HWANG
Subtitle translation by Soo-hyun Yang
Modify by Blue-Bird™